<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Topics on Smart Fruit Phenomics Team</title><link>https://brleme.github.io/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Research Topics on Smart Fruit Phenomics Team</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; Smart Fruit Phenomics Team, Blueberry Breeding Program - 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:10:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://brleme.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Field High-throughput Phenomics</title><link>https://brleme.github.io/projects/proj_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://brleme.github.io/projects/proj_1/</guid><description>Yield prediction is an increasingly researched topic aimed at boosting productivity in agricultural settings. Leveraging recent advancements in AI, particularly in Image Processing and Computer Vision, our team focuses on innovative approaches to improve yield prediction in blueberry crops. Besides, we are interested in all the pipeline involved for predictions from devices for autonomously collecting data, field mapping and identification, to the data representation and further temporal analyses.
Blueberries present unique challenges due to their intricate plant morphology.</description></item><item><title>Multimodal Fruit Quality Analyses</title><link>https://brleme.github.io/projects/proj_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://brleme.github.io/projects/proj_2/</guid><description>Advancing Fruit Quality Assessment through Multimodal Data Acquisition
Fruit quality assessment stands as a pivotal area of exploration, aimed at enhancing the value and consumer satisfaction associated with fruit features. Leveraging cutting-edge advancements in computer vision, force sensing technology, and additional sensory inputs, our project aims to the development of a modular device designed for comprehensive data acquisition of blueberry fruits. By integrating a variety of sensors, including force sensors, imaging sensors, and more, we are seeks to elevate the accuracy and efficiency of fruit quality evaluation.</description></item><item><title>Speed Breeding in Blueberries</title><link>https://brleme.github.io/projects/proj_3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://brleme.github.io/projects/proj_3/</guid><description>Speed breeding is indeed an exciting agricultural technique with the potential to revolutionize the blueberry industry. The traditional breeding methods for blueberries have been time-consuming, hindering the development of new cultivars with desirable traits. However, speed breeding offers a promising solution to this challenge by significantly reducing the breeding timeline.
By leveraging controlled environments and optimized growth conditions, speed breeding accelerates the growth cycle and reduces generation times for blueberry plants.</description></item></channel></rss>