<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Smart Fruit Phenomics Team</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Smart Fruit Phenomics Team</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; Smart Fruit Phenomics Team, Blueberry Breeding Program - 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:10:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sfp-team.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Field High-throughput Phenomics</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/projects/proj_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/projects/proj_1/</guid><description>Yield prediction is an increasingly researched topic aimed at boosting productivity in agricultural settings. Leveraging recent advancements in AI, particularly in Image Processing and Computer Vision, our team focuses on innovative approaches to improve yield prediction in blueberry crops. Besides, we are interested in all the pipeline involved for predictions from devices for autonomously collecting data, field mapping and identification, to the data representation and further temporal analyses.
Blueberries present unique challenges due to their intricate plant morphology.</description></item><item><title>Multimodal Fruit Quality Analyses</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/projects/proj_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/projects/proj_2/</guid><description>Advancing Fruit Quality Assessment through Multimodal Data Acquisition
Fruit quality assessment stands as a pivotal area of exploration, aimed at enhancing the value and consumer satisfaction associated with fruit features. Leveraging cutting-edge advancements in computer vision, force sensing technology, and additional sensory inputs, our project aims to the development of a modular device designed for comprehensive data acquisition of blueberry fruits. By integrating a variety of sensors, including force sensors, imaging sensors, and more, we are seeks to elevate the accuracy and efficiency of fruit quality evaluation.</description></item><item><title>Speed Breeding in Blueberries</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/projects/proj_3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 16:10:22 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/projects/proj_3/</guid><description>Speed breeding is indeed an exciting agricultural technique with the potential to revolutionize the blueberry industry. The traditional breeding methods for blueberries have been time-consuming, hindering the development of new cultivars with desirable traits. However, speed breeding offers a promising solution to this challenge by significantly reducing the breeding timeline.
By leveraging controlled environments and optimized growth conditions, speed breeding accelerates the growth cycle and reduces generation times for blueberry plants.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/positions/pos1/aaa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/positions/pos1/aaa/</guid><description>The Smart Fruit Phenomics Team at the Blueberry Breeding and Genomics Laboratory is looking for students interested in applying engineering solutions for classifying blueberries. The team study methods for using robotic devices for improving multimodal phenotypic data and provide plant breeders with more accurate data.
We are looking for students with experience / interest on the following areas
dsadsa dsadas
Computer vision / A.I. (Yolo, R-CNN models, autoencoders) Speech recognition / A.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/positions/pos2/aaa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/positions/pos2/aaa/</guid><description>The Smart Fruit Phenomics Team at the Blueberry Breeding and Genomics Laboratory is looking for students interested in applying engineering solutions for classifying blueberries. The team study methods for using robotic devices for improving multimodal phenotypic data and provide plant breeders with more accurate data.
We are looking for students with experience / interest on the following areas:
dsadsa dsadas #- Computer vision / A.I. (Yolo, R-CNN models, autoencoders) #- Speech recognition / A.</description></item><item><title>Bruno LEME</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/bruno/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/bruno/</guid><description>I am currently a Postdoctoral Associate, responsible for the Smart Fruit Phenomics Team in the Blueberry breeding and Genomics Laboratory at University of Florida. The team studies methods of implementing engineering solutions for acquiring multimodal phenotypic data in crops, which can be used for assisting breeders and growers obtaining faster and more reliable data.
I have over 8 years of engineering experience in academia and industry. Before joining the University of Florida, I was a researcher at the National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology - AIST (Tokyo, Japan), working on teaching by demonstration approaches for robot manipulation from September 2021 to January 2023.</description></item><item><title>Dylan Clark</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/dylan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/dylan/</guid><description>I am a new graduate student with a background in plant breeding and ecophysiology. I graduated with my B.S in Plant Science from the University of Florida and have worked for UF in some capacity for the past 4 years. Most of my previous work revolved around heat tolerance and drought tolerance in crops and natural ecosystems. My most notable project was the developement of a high-throughput system for measuring thermal-tolerance in breeding programs and natural ecosystems.</description></item><item><title>Felix Enciso-Rodriguez</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/felix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/felix/</guid><description>I am a biologist with wide-ranging experience in bioinformatics and molecular approaches for gene identification, gene mapping, and molecular characterization of germplasm collections from orphan and cultivated crops. I have implemented genomic selection strategies as well as genome editing approaches in staple crops such as potatoes (resulting in two patents) and blueberries. The combination of such techniques, along with germplasm characterization and gene discovery, has allowed me to contribute to accelerating the generation of new potato varieties and exploiting heterosis in advanced breeding lines.</description></item><item><title>Hemanth Pedamallu</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/hemanth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/hemanth/</guid><description>I am a dedicated and results-driven computer science student with a passion for pushing the boundaries of technology to solve real-world problems. My commitment to research is reflected in my publication on VoIP Spam Detection using Machine Learning in IEEE&amp;rsquo;s prestigious digital library. This publication underscores my dedication to advancing knowledge in the field. Beyond the technical realm, I am passionate about enhancing websites, both in terms of user interfaces and APIs.</description></item><item><title>TJ Schultz</title><link>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/tj/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sfp-team.github.io/members/tj/</guid><description>I hold a B.S. in Computer Science with a minor in Mathematics and an A.S. in Programming and Analysis. I am currently employed at the University of Florida Blueberry Breeding and Genomics Lab, writing code for automated phenotyping projects. I have experience with building web pages, object-oriented programs with GUI elements, databases using SQL, mathematical modeling programs, machine/deep learning applications, and computer vision applications.</description></item></channel></rss>